<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jorgicio's Crib</title><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://jorgicio.github.io/</id><updated>2015-05-07T20:15:30-03:00</updated><entry><title>The miller, the boy, and their donkey: An Æsop's fable</title><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/the-miller-the-boy-and-their-donkey-an-aesops-fable.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-07T20:15:30-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:jorgicio.github.io,2015-05-07:the-miller-the-boy-and-their-donkey-an-aesops-fable.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="The guys on the fable." src="http://jorgicio.github.io/images/donkey.jpg" title="The guys on the fable." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A miller, his son, and their donkey, were going on the way to the market in the other side oy their town across a bridge; then, someone told them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are you doing? Don't be silly, you have a donkey, so why don't ride it?.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the man put the boy on the animal for riding. Then, another people yelled:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a lazy boy, making his father walk!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The miller took his son and put him down. Then, the man rode the donkey and continued their walk. Another people yelled:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poor kid! He was walking while his father was riding the donkey! What a silly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, the miller took the boy up, and now, both are riding the donkey.
Another people went to yell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poor donkey! Don't you think is a shame to put a lot of weight on that animal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The miller and the boy, tired of what people say, grabbed a wood and a rope, then tied the donkey by the legs to it, and both carried the animal hung up. Then, all the people that were watching it, laughed. When both are crossing the bridge, they couldn't carry the animal anymore, so it slipped and dropped to the river below. As being tied and unable to swim, the donkey drowned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moral: Try to please everybody, so you won't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know the key to success, but I know that the key to failure, is trying to please everybody.&lt;br&gt;
- Woody Allen&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="social"></category><category term="fable"></category><category term="miller"></category><category term="boy"></category><category term="donkey"></category><category term="aesop"></category></entry><entry><title>Bio Bio is writing articles in English!</title><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/bio-bio-is-writing-articles-in-english.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-07T01:45:10-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:jorgicio.github.io,2015-05-07:bio-bio-is-writing-articles-in-english.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm a &lt;a href="http://www.biobiochile.cl"&gt;Bio-Bio&lt;/a&gt; frequent reader, so when I started to read news in English, the first thought that came to my mind is: &lt;abbr title="Seriously, WTF?!"&gt;WTF&lt;/abbr&gt;?!
As the feature is new there, failures were welcome. And they were being corrected thanks to comments from readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the way, news I'm talking about, is &lt;abbr title="Current President of Chile."&gt;Bachelet&lt;/abbr&gt; announcing the cabinet reshuffle... on a talk show, not a national television network (duh!). You can read it &lt;a href="http://www.biobiochile.cl/2015/05/07/chilean-president-michelle-bachelet-face-crisis-asking-her-entire-cabinet-to-resign.shtml"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="news"></category><category term="bio bio"></category><category term="english"></category><category term="Bachelet"></category><category term="cabinet reshuffle"></category></entry><entry><title>Pacquiao v/s Mayweather. Why is it so important?</title><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/pacquiao-vs-mayweather-why-is-it-so-important.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-02T21:45:10-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:jorgicio.github.io,2015-05-02:pacquiao-vs-mayweather-why-is-it-so-important.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src="http://jorgicio.github.io/images/pacquiao.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Look at those guys. What relaxed are they.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this fight is the most awaited in latter days. But, well... that's just a fight like any other in the world. Also, I bet both Pacquiao any Mayweather are not so known before this event, so... What's the matter? When everybody is interested in boxing since? I respect some people that follow both guys since their careers, but why everybody? That's too &lt;del&gt;fucking&lt;/del&gt; mainstream. And that's something I wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, with this, that's not a matter of you can watch it or not, but everybody got me fed up with that people comments every 5 minutes what's happening on TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I got fed up with the TV, specially if it's about showbiz world, but that's something I'll comment in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="manny pacquiao"></category><category term="floyd mayweather"></category><category term="boxing"></category><category term="fight"></category></entry><entry><title>Tracking the site</title><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/tracking-the-site.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-02T13:33:10-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:jorgicio.github.io,2015-05-02:tracking-the-site.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;z35W7z4v9z8w&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you know, I submitted this blog to the &lt;a href="http://feedshark.brainbliss.com/"&gt;Feed Shark&lt;/a&gt; service, and they asked me to create a new post with this code, so... there it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="tracking"></category><category term="feedshark"></category></entry><entry><title>Living with Dvorak, the keyboard</title><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/living-with-dvorak-the-keyboard.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-02T12:23:10-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:jorgicio.github.io,2015-05-02:living-with-dvorak-the-keyboard.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src="http://jorgicio.github.io/images/dvorak_spanish.png" title="Dvorak Spanish" &gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;The Spanish Dvorak Keyboard.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dvorak_Keyboard"&gt;Dvorak keyboard&lt;/a&gt; user since November, 2014. Exactly, the same day &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chespirito"&gt;Chespirito&lt;/a&gt; died. And since that, I had to do some modifications in my daily life. As expected, in the first days, I experienced some clumsiness; but now, I'm more experienced than before. However, there are things I noticed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still mistake between the keys "n" and "s", "m" and "w", and the combinations "tr" and "rt". Or some keys besides them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you compare between the Spanish Dvorak, and the standard one, will notice "h" and "r" keys are swapped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can't do the "asdf" combination anymore. Or some similar combinations that use those keys, just for leisure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "wasd" combination is now ",aoe". It's weird to use a punctuation mark as an arrow key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can read the "&lt;abbr title="&amp;quot;Conchetumadre&amp;quot;, the Chilean counterpart of &amp;quot;Motherfucker&amp;quot;."&gt;CTM&lt;/abbr&gt;" keys across the rows. If you're Chilean, may get the joke.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The key "a" never moved when switching between one layout and another. Just compare the QWERTY and the DVORAK ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As well-known, vowels are in the 2nd row, and are the first 5 keys there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There's no a &lt;abbr title="Latin American (Spanish, of course)."&gt;Latam&lt;/abbr&gt; variant for the Dvorak Keyboard... &lt;a href="https://github.com/flobosg/latam-dvorak"&gt;yet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And yes... indeed, typing is faster than QWERTY.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want to try this layout, try to do it when you have some free time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;abbr title="GRand Unified Boot. The bootloader for GNU/Linux."&gt;GRUB&lt;/abbr&gt; only works with QWERTY... unless I may do some some tweak.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now I'm clumsy at re-using a QWERTY keyboard when available. Yes, it's something I have to deal. You know, everything moves around the QWERTY one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The "XD" emoticon requires some elongation in the fingers. But nothing impossible to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dvorak is for hipsters. QWERTY? Too mainstream!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you want to try a Dvorak layout, may not regret that. But try to not forget what learned with QWERTY, because you'll need it in some time in the (not so far) future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="dvorak"></category><category term="keyboard"></category><category term="qwerty"></category></entry><entry><title>To copy, or not to copy</title><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/to-copy-or-not-to-copy.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-05-02T02:23:10-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:jorgicio.github.io,2015-05-02:to-copy-or-not-to-copy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, as a summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some days ago, in my &lt;a href="http://www.usm.cl"&gt;university&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=911119055615127&amp;amp;id=145847642142276"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; published on Facebook accused some students to copy a homework for a course called Programming (&lt;em&gt;Programación&lt;/em&gt;, as its original name), and if all involved people doesn't pronounce before April 30th, goes to the universitary committee. Rules and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that if anybody copies something, there's no problem if gives some credit for that. Anyways, everybody does it. But neither is for doing it shamelessly. Wisdom must be transmitted to everybody; but if not, it dies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people has not something better to do as of punish someone for just copying something, and not for something worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curiously: my career supports, in part, the opensource.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Note that the statement is in Spanish.&lt;br /&gt;
PS 2: &lt;em&gt;Programming&lt;/em&gt; is for 1st year students. And it's in Python.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="copyright"></category><category term=""></category></entry><entry><title>#Fifigate, or the importance of the security in the Social Media</title><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/fifigate-or-the-importance-of-the-security-in-social-media.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-16T00:14:10-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:jorgicio.github.io,2015-04-16:fifigate-or-the-importance-of-the-security-in-social-media.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src="http://jorgicio.github.io/images/fifi.png" title="Dafuq?" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Ok, this is not what I mean; but at least, it's a little bit innocent. &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In latter days, the Fifi video is one of the most commented in Chile, and got the title of trend for a few days. However, I won't share, nor watch it because of &lt;a href="http://www.publimetro.cl/nota/cronica/compartiste-o-solo-viste-el-video-de-la-fifi-estas-son-las-penas-a-las-que-te-expones/xIQodi!eTtIA1QFIzRhc/"&gt;obvious reasons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well... as I understood, she mistook on trust her so-called "friends". Supposedly, she trusted her passwords, and it may be the root of the leakage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some years ago, I started to learn the concept of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_engineering_(security)"&gt;social engineering&lt;/a&gt;. A sort of psychological way to get information from another people. It also could be the cause of the incident of the Wena Naty, ocurred in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, I could not had a personal opinion about this until some closer people, as such as a relative (or the Fifi herself, as a preference), speaks about the situation. As happened with a Paloma, a Fifi relative (not specified who is), who sent a letter what's read by Nicolás Copano. Unfortunately, the audio is in Spanish, and there's no subs. Anyway, I leave it here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="320" height="240"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/8WR62e8OFkk'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did I learn about that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don't trust some confidential information to anybody.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you did that, change passwords frequently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create some perfect passwords! &lt;a href="http://www.digitaltrends.com/mobile/edward-snowden-john-oliver-passwords/"&gt;Edward Snowden&lt;/a&gt; teaches us how to. Also, try to do this with things you can remember. Use the mnemotecnics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It's not working leaving rooms locked, if the main door is open to anybody.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch out about file permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, another thing I want to comment, is about morbid interest in that topic. Taking videos or photos doing some intimate or sexual acts, doesn't turn that person a whore, if commited to that. If leakage is done by third parties, it's not necessarily her fault. Also, the subject is sensitive because all people involved in that incident, are underage, at least in Chile. So please, stop morbid interests at sharing or storaging the video. It can also be an illicit act. Respect Fifi, and leave her alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="fifi"></category><category term="social networks"></category><category term="porn"></category><category term="social media"></category><category term="leakage"></category><category term="computer science"></category></entry><entry><title>Where's sexism?</title><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/wheres-sexism.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-04-15T01:14:15-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:jorgicio.github.io,2015-04-15:wheres-sexism.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src="http://jorgicio.github.io/images/feminism.png" title="Dafuq?" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Translation from main thread: &lt;i&gt;If I'm a (female) engineer, why in my diploma, does it say (male) 'engineer'?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Translation from comment below: &lt;i&gt;I don't know if 160 people like this because of its level of ridiculousness, or because they agree with the complaint. Anyways, I think that's a fuck-around post, I refuse to believe someone seriously posted this bullshit, hahahahaha.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting with this, Spanish language is gender-nominative by default. We have, in some instances, deal with gender nouns when available, when in English, that's not necessary (at least, in situations like that). As an example, the word 'engineer' can mean any male or female; while in Spanish, we have to point exactly what one means. However, in formal terms, the gender is meaningless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what's the point of this? Some people, like that girl, is overreacting on topics like this. From times and times ago, the term &lt;em&gt;&lt;abbr title="(Male) engineer."&gt;ingeniero&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is always used in formal documents like a diploma, but it doesn't address to a gender in particular. However, some people like her, doesn't get that. Because of that, feminism is misunderstood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this is why I prefer &lt;abbr title="Advocates equality of rights for everyone, no matter the gender."&gt;egalitarism&lt;/abbr&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Answering the question, sexism is on an only place: on some people's minds that doesn't what feminism really means. Persons that think there's a &lt;abbr title="Patriarchy, patriarchy everyhwere."&gt;patriarchy&lt;/abbr&gt; because of a (simple) male noun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is what I believe in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="videobox"&gt;
                &lt;iframe width="360" height="240"
                    src='https://www.youtube.com/embed/c3gMELlrO3E'
                    frameborder='0' webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen
                    allowFullScreen&gt;
                &lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category><category term="jorgicio"></category><category term="social"></category><category term="gender role"></category><category term="feminism"></category></entry><entry><title>Back to the origins</title><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/back-to-the-origins.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-24T00:47:36-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:jorgicio.github.io,2015-03-24:back-to-the-origins.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src="http://jorgicio.github.io/images/iquique_family.jpg" width="360" title="My northern family" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;My northern family&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well... as some people (closer to me) knows, I was born in Iquique in 1986. Because of some things of the life, I moved to Ovalle when was 3 months. After that, I got back to the north in February, 1994. I was 7 yet, but I was able to understand some things about my origins. 21 years later, &lt;abbr title="Yes, here in Chile, it's summer, when in northern countries, it's winter. Yes, Christmastime is very hot here."&gt;in past summer&lt;/abbr&gt;, I got back again, and noticed how the family grew up, and it's still going on that. Lots of emotions came here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I recently went to Iquique, all parties are in family. So I'll go frequently. (No, La Serena and Ovalle won't be forgotten!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My birth place itself grew up, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found some things I must noticed before, and changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My family is of &lt;abbr title="A minoritary ethnic group which people can be found in the Greater North of Chile, in Southern Peru, and Bolivia. They live mostly in the Andean high plains, a.k.a Altiplano."&gt;Aymara&lt;/abbr&gt; descent, so me too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have some cute (female) cousins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oneself can move easily within the city. Taxis are cheaper than in other cities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Culture itself is very closer to their Andean roots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The past year earthquake (May, 2014) still shows its scars. Things in Iquique are still not fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mayor is an asshole. (Well... that's not any novelty)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In summer, it's so hot, that I didn't need to turn the heater on. (Anyway, it's broken)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I want to go again, I hope it'd be for a month. And in aeroplane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All my family (in both sides, maternal and fraternal) is very awesome. And things like that, make me worth them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XOXO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="personal"></category><category term="jorgicio"></category><category term="iquique"></category></entry><entry><title>My first post here</title><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/my-first-post-here.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-03-22T22:47:44-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:jorgicio.github.io,2015-03-22:my-first-post-here.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hello, World!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or so it must begin. Anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm starting this alternative blog because I want to try the benefits of &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, a blog-oriented platform made in Python, what's my favourite programming language. Also, I want to improve my practice in English, so I'll write the posts in that language. Maybe I'll include some other languages, specially Spanish, my mother tongue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wait for a description about myself, it won't be here, but in a page that will be available... soon. Meanwhile, you can watch everything about me in &lt;a href="http://www.jorgicio.net"&gt;my personal site&lt;/a&gt; (in Spanish).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I may learn about this, and having some break, I'll be posting here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Any suggestions are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="jorgicio"></category></entry></feed>