<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Jorgicio's Crib - personal</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://jorgicio.github.io/feeds/personal.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2015-05-02T21:45:10-03:00</updated><entry><title>Pacquiao v/s Mayweather. Why is it so important?</title><link href="/pacquiao-vs-mayweather-why-is-it-so-important.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-02T21:45:10-03:00</published><updated>2015-05-02T21:45:10-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-05-02:/pacquiao-vs-mayweather-why-is-it-so-important.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are lots of fights in the world. Why is this so important?&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src="/images/pacquiao.jpg"&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Look at those guys. What relaxed are they.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know this fight is the most awaited in latter days. But, well... that's just a fight like any other in the world. Also, I bet both Pacquiao any Mayweather are not so known before this event, so... What's the matter? When everybody is interested in boxing since? I respect some people that follow both guys since their careers, but why everybody? That's too &lt;del&gt;fucking&lt;/del&gt; mainstream. And that's something I wonder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, with this, that's not a matter of you can watch it or not, but everybody got me fed up with that people comments every 5 minutes what's happening on TV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I got fed up with the TV, specially if it's about showbiz world, but that's something I'll comment in a future post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="manny pacquiao"></category><category term="floyd mayweather"></category><category term="boxing"></category><category term="fight"></category></entry><entry><title>Tracking the site</title><link href="/tracking-the-site.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-05-02T13:33:10-03:00</published><updated>2015-05-02T13:33:10-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-05-02:/tracking-the-site.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;z35W7z4v9z8w&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;z35W7z4v9z8w&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, you know, I submitted this blog to the &lt;a href="http://feedshark.brainbliss.com/"&gt;Feed Shark&lt;/a&gt; service, and they asked me to create a new post with this code, so... there it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="tracking"></category><category term="feedshark"></category></entry><entry><title>Back to the origins</title><link href="/back-to-the-origins.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-24T00:47:36-03:00</published><updated>2015-03-24T00:47:36-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-03-24:/back-to-the-origins.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The best of my trip to my birth place&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src="/images/iquique_family.jpg" width="360" title="My northern family" /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;My northern family&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well... as some people (closer to me) knows, I was born in Iquique in 1986. Because of some things of the life, I moved to Ovalle when was 3 months. After that, I got back to the north in February, 1994. I was 7 yet, but I was able to understand some things about my origins. 21 years later, &lt;abbr title="Yes, here in Chile, it's summer, when in northern countries, it's winter. Yes, Christmastime is very hot here."&gt;in past summer&lt;/abbr&gt;, I got back again, and noticed how the family grew up, and it's still going on that. Lots of emotions came here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I recently went to Iquique, all parties are in family. So I'll go frequently. (No, La Serena and Ovalle won't be forgotten!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My birth place itself grew up, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found some things I must noticed before, and changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My family is of &lt;abbr title="A minoritary ethnic group which people can be found in the Greater North of Chile, in Southern Peru, and Bolivia. They live mostly in the Andean high plains, a.k.a Altiplano."&gt;Aymara&lt;/abbr&gt; descent, so me too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have some cute (female) cousins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oneself can move easily within the city. Taxis are cheaper than in other cities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Culture itself is very closer to their Andean roots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The past year earthquake (May, 2014) still shows its scars. Things in Iquique are still not fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mayor is an asshole. (Well... that's not any novelty)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In summer, it's so hot, that I didn't need to turn the heater on. (Anyway, it's broken)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I want to go again, I hope it'd be for a month. And in aeroplane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All my family (in both sides, maternal and fraternal) is very awesome. And things like that, make me worth them all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XOXO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="personal"></category><category term="jorgicio"></category><category term="iquique"></category></entry><entry><title>My first post here</title><link href="/my-first-post-here.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-22T22:47:44-03:00</published><updated>2015-03-22T22:47:44-03:00</updated><author><name>Jorgicio</name></author><id>tag:None,2015-03-22:/my-first-post-here.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Starting with this blog&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Hello, World!&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or so it must begin. Anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm starting this alternative blog because I want to try the benefits of &lt;a href="http://blog.getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, a blog-oriented platform made in Python, what's my favourite programming language. Also, I want to improve my practice in English, so I'll write the posts in that language. Maybe I'll include some other languages, specially Spanish, my mother tongue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wait for a description about myself, it won't be here, but in a page that will be available... soon. Meanwhile, you can watch everything about me in &lt;a href="http://www.jorgicio.net"&gt;my personal site&lt;/a&gt; (in Spanish).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I may learn about this, and having some break, I'll be posting here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Any suggestions are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jorgicio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="python"></category><category term="personal"></category><category term="jorgicio"></category></entry></feed>